"IT IS NOT THE STRONGEST OF THE SPECIES
THAT SURVIVES. NOR THE MOST INTELLIGENT.
IT IS THE ONE THAT IS
MOST ADAPTABLE TO CHANGE."
BASED ON THE WORK OF CHARLES DARWIN
NORTH PACIFIC OCEAN
MISSION OCEAN ORIGINS
PROJECT "EVOLUTION"
I'm here on what's known as
the "seventh continent."
a mass of refuse and garbage
over 3 million kilometers in size.
four to six times bigger than France.
Almost a million birds
and other marine mammals
perish each year after swallowing plastic.
- Ugh. it's awful.
- Come on. it was good.
- It's boring. It's numbers.
- It's not boring.
You know that. Go on. You got this.
Hey. You're amazing.
- I love you. I love you.
- Okay. okay.
- All right. And let's go.
- Okay. Roll it.
Action.
For the last three years.
with the help of my team.
we've been tagging
different species of shark.
- After which. we use the biological...
- Sophia!
We got a signal. guys. Are you ready?
Let's go!
Southeast.
You stay at six meters and wait for her!
All right. Let's go. let's go!
Right. boys. We're diving in five minutes!
The sample units are loaded.
we just need the cameras.
They're already on the cameras.
Just don't break them this time.
Can't wait to dive into
all this trash. Yummy.
- Distance?
- Five hundred meters.
She's coming closer.
All right. boys. same as usual.
You follow me. you keep close.
Tom. Sam. you group up.
- Juan.
- Yeah?
- You'll be with me.
- Yeah.
We stabilize at six meters.
we wait for orders from Sophia. Got it?
- Roger that. captain.
- Okay. boss.
Juanito?
Juan?
I hear ya. Soph. It's all good.
We're starting our descent.
Right. Stay on track. boys.
We can't let her get away again.
Finally back in your element. Sam?
What element? This one?
All right. wise guys.
where are you?
Descending to six meters.
All clear.
I just hope she sticks around.
Don't worry. I won't let her go.
Radar echo at 70 meters.
Which way?
South-southeast.
- Okay. we'll keep an eye out.
- Yeah.
Wait. Stop.
Seeing this. Sophia?
Another baby sperm whale
caught in the nets.
That's the second in three weeks.
It must've suffered for days.
I'm gonna go check it out.
Wait here. boys.
Its stomach is full of plastic.
Chris. we need to focus
on Beacon Seven.
Hang on.
Are you getting this?
It's a bite mark.
Sure. but can you see?
It's massive.
Chris. she's approaching. 30 meters.
Ah! What the hell? What the hell?
- Chris?
- Chris. you good?
You okay?
Yeah. yeah. It's fine.
She's not ours.
I see other ones.
Hang on a sec.
Since when do makos hunt in packs?
- What the hell's going on? Sophia?
- I don't understand.
They're all females.
And a lot of them.
Do you see their fins?
- Yeah.
- That's not normal.
Yeah.
It's a similar hypertrophy to Lilith.
There's about ten of them here.
- Weird.
- Can you hear me?
They seem nervous.
Security protocol.
- Sophia...
- Oh no.
- Sophia. what do we do?
- Stay calm. Just keep a safe distance.
You're fine.
Signal ping south.
Chris. she's coming.
What the fuck? Are you seeing this?
Holy shit. You sure that's ours?
- She's at least five meters.
- She's at least seven. man.
I don't get it.
That should be Lilith in front of you.
It's her. all right.
No. that's impossible.
Three months ago. she was only 2.5 meters.
I'm sure it's her. Sophia.
Look. Beacon Seven.
Okay. what do we do?
I don't understand.
How is this possible?
We gotta head back up. It's too dangerous.
Hang on. wait. We still need the sample.
Yeah. well. easy for you to say.
Fine. then. I'll do it.
Unbelievable! This is such bullshit.
We have no choice. Chris.
We have to understand what happened.
It'll be okay.
Make sure to face her head-on
so she's not surprised.
That's a good distance.
Easy does it.
Yeah. two seconds.
Oh shit!
You okay?
- Yeah. I'm okay.
- We got it. Come on back up.
You hear that. boys?
Mission accomplished!
Hey. Chris. relax.
You scared or what?
Hang on a second.
I think she's coming back.
- Anyone have eyes on Beacon Seven?
- Where'd she go? She was there!
Chris?
Where the hell did she go?
Do you see her?
I saw her two seconds ago! Where are you?
Chris. what's the matter?
I saw her behind us. Where is she?
Do you see her?
- Chris?
- No! No!
Chris. there's no image!
Chris!
- Chris!
- Sam!
Get out of there!
Chris. are you okay?
Juan! Answer me!
Ugh!
Sophia!
Sophia! Stop!
Sophia. no!
Sophia!
Chris! Chris!
Get back on the boat!
UNDER PARIS
3 YEARS LATER
Check it. I got something!
Pretty nice.
It's cool. let's see
if we have anything else here.
I got something.
- Wait! Wait!
- We can get it.
I think it's stuck.
- You okay?
- Yeah. yeah.
What is that?
- Little help over here?
- Got it.
- Everything okay here?
- Thanks.
- How was it?
- It's clean.
Adama for Caro. Once Adil's done
with the journalists. we'll clear out.
Okay. understood.
We'll see you soon.
- We're done here. guys.
- Okay.
Was this an unusual case?
We find these kinds of shells
all the time in the Seine.
With our colleagues from the Central Lab
of the Police Prefecture.
we've already fished out about 100.
The two who found it did the right thing.
- Angèle for Adil.
- Excuse me.
It's okay. I'll handle the press.
Time for the triathlon security briefing.
You go ahead. I'll catch up.
- Have to go. sorry. She'll take over.
- Thanks.
- Hello.
- Any comments. commander?
I'd like to reassure you. these shells
didn't have any ignition systems.
There was no danger.
- Nice work. bro.
- Thanks.
River Police. Control Bravo...
We're done! Gotta get to Hotel de Ville
for the triathlon briefing.
Over.
Let's go.
Hey. you with the kayak!
That's not allowed!
Okay. okay! Damn it!
What in the world is going on today?
Which of you would devote
your whole life to protecting the whales?
Me! Me! Me!
That's the question they asked me
when I signed on to protect the oceans.
If the oceans can't survive.
then neither can us humans.
What makes a living ocean?
Diversity in the ecosystem.
That means it has lots of fish
living and thriving.
but also algae. coral. plants...
If we can't save life in the ocean.
we won't be able to save ourselves.
- Ma'am?
- Yes?
Isn't it too late to save the oceans?
Well. there was a man
named Paul Watson who said that...
The Internet says your whole team
was eaten by sharks. Is that true?
- Victor. Get rid of your phone. Now!
- But...
- That's enough.
- I was just asking a question.
Look. her face has gone red.
Marine creatures
require specific conditions to survive.
Our center prides itself on replicating
habitats they'd experience in the wild.
from careful temperature regulation
to food diversity.
Sophia!
Sophia! Ms. Assalas!
I'm really sorry to bother you.
Ms. Assalas. I just...
I just have to talk to you for a sec.
I've been following your work forever.
All of it.
- Migration based on climate...
- I'm sorry. it's a bad time.
Beacon Seven!
I know where it is.
Well. this is it. SOS.
SOS... Save our Seas.
You've never heard about us?
It's our ocean defense organization.
When we first started.
we figured it'd never take off.
but now it's starting to get
really serious.
We do what you do.
Well. I mean. as best as we can.
You've always been our inspiration.
We've been building on your work.
You describe how sometimes
nature can trigger
all sorts of changes in behavior.
Right. also. to protect the sharks.
we've been connecting to their beacons.
And as soon as they're in danger
because of...
Well. if they're being tracked by poachers
for their fins. we can disconnect them.
As I dive deeper into the ocean...
Sophia. over here.
Ben. Ben. Ben. Ben...
Wait. wait. wait. Two seconds.
What's going on?
We spotted a trawler near Ulysses.
I'm gonna get him out.
Where is he?
Spain.
No fishing for you today. guys.
- Ta-da!
- What is it? Show me.
Get Beacon Seven.
- Ben. Beacon Seven.
- Yeah...
- Ben. please. Show her Beacon Seven.
- Right. Uh...
Right.
Beacon Seven. Beacon Seven. Beacon Seven...
And there.
Look.
That's impossible.
Our servers. they're well-protected.
That can't be my beacon.
I mean. well-protected or not. these days
you can access anything. See that?
We caught her tracker
three weeks ago in Le Havre.
After that. she swam back up the Seine.
Lilith's been here for three days.
In the heart of Paris.
No. it's impossible. It's fresh water.
Bull sharks breed in fresh water.
so we thought that could explain...
She's a mako.
You were right.
With the effects
of climate change and pollution.
the sharks have changed their behavior.
She got here by mistake
and now she's just trying to survive.
Even if by some miracle it is my beacon.
it must have just come loose.
And drifted against the current.
that makes sense to you?
Wouldn't it have sunk?
It's really important
we help her get back.
Otherwise. she'll die.
Me and Ben can communicate with her.
Are you insane?
She's a shark. not a poodle.
Just dive with us.
I'm going to prove you wrong.
- In the Seine?
- Yeah.
We're going in tonight.
I don't know why I came here.
There was an accident last night.
The Pont Marie.
A car went right off the bridge.
but they never found the driver.
Sophia!
...and more sustainable planet for all.
We got here less than an hour ago.
and we've already spotted
two whale sharks.
Right there. See them. Sophia?
Wait. look! A third one!
- Oh wow. that one's huge!
- You seeing this?
- So beautiful!
- It's because of deep drop-offs.
Oh bravo. Great job.
Wow. Three hours to repair a motor.
that's gotta be a new record.
- Come on! Let's play!
- Nice job!
- Come on. Race ya there!
- Come on. big guy!
Four. three. two. one...
Happy New Year!
Whoo!
- Whoo-hoo!
- Hey! Make a wish. babe. I love you!
- Hey. watch it.
Whoo!
Go for it. Chris.
- Just keep a safe distance.
- Hang on a sec.
Chris. there's no image!
That's impossible.
It's Mika. leave a message.
Mika.
Mika. it's Sophia.
Call me back. please.
Yeah.
Okay. if you're in trouble.
you pull the line and get out. Got it?
- And what about you?
- I'll be fine.
You figure kisses
will get you off the hook?
- If anything happens. you get out. Okay?
- Okay.
Mika. hurry. Get out.
Police!
Can you get out of the water. please?
Get out of the water. now!
Why were you diving
in the middle of the night?
So I'm not allowed to clean the Seine?
You were cleaning the Seine?
Yeah.
And who owns that boat?
It's mine. What do you mean?
- We're going to the station.
- No.
If everything checks out.
you can go home. Okay?
Nils! Let's pass by Ile St-Louis
and check on the others.
Okay.
Kiki. stay close to me.
Have you heard from Roger?
We haven't seen him in a long time.
Hey. guys! How are ya?
Oh. hey!
You doing okay?
- Here. we brought you some stuff.
- Oh. That's slick. man.
- Here. This one should fit.
- Quality gear.
- Perfect.
- Is it your size?
What else have we got here?
- Team's here.
- Ah!
- Hey. Markus. catch!
- Yeah.
Give me some slack.
Hey. Adewale.
- You good. chief?
- All good. thanks.
How's the lady? Looking beautiful.
- Ooh!
- Sorry. are we distracting you. Adewale?
Are we all set? They have all their stuff?
They're ready to go
and we gave them a hand.
It's under control. chief.
You guys were a big help.
We're gone tomorrow. no problem.
Sorry.
but it'll be three weeks. max.
The mayor wants the docks
cleaned for the triathlon.
Don't worry. And besides. Kiki and I
are going to have a front-row seat.
That's perfect.
- Well. happy reading.
- Thanks.
- See you at the station?
- Yup.
- Okay. easing out.
- Here we go.
- Give it some gas.
- You got it.
Let's go!
What took you so long?
We picked her up
at the accident site near Pont Marie.
She was in the water in diving gear.
Fine. Adama. can you handle this?
Chief. I have to unload
all this gear first.
- It's okay. I got it.
- Me too. If you need help.
Caro's got it under control. I'm off.
Call my cell if you need me.
See you tomorrow.
Good night. chief.
Wait. wait. I'm going first.
- Follow me.
- Nils.
- Yeah?
- You're still on duty. right?
- Yeah. why?
- Put on your vest.
You're not
a firefighter anymore. sunshine!
Last I checked.
this wasn't the army. either.
You wouldn't last an hour
in the army. man.
154 WORLD WAR II SHELLS FOUND
UNDER THE IENA BRIDGE
Coffee?
So am I allowed to go home now?
Why were you diving?
Does it have to do with the accident?
We have something for you.
20-10 reporting in.
Sugar?
15-5. this is dispatch.
Domestic dispute call just came in.
I sent you the address.
I think you'll recognize it. Confirm.
So...
Explain to me.
why were you searching the car?
- Damn it.
- I asked you a question!
- Why were you diving?
- There's a shark in the Seine. Happy now?
You wanna waste time? That's fine.
All right. You think I'm an idiot.
We're going to start all over again.
What's your name?
Adil! We have an emergency.
Come on. sweetheart. Time to go.
Aww...
Look. Daddy. Look!
There's little fishies.
Fuck. No...
- Where. honey?
- Did you see?
Yeah.
Hey. you! Get away from there!
Get back up here now!
Hey. you can't speak
to my daughter like that.
- Sorry.
- What's wrong with you?
I'm really sorry.
- Hello?
- Come on.
Yeah. it's me.
Glad you could make it.
This way.
Morning.
- Adil Faez. sergeant.
- Sophia Assalas.
I believe you know each other?
- I told them to call you. I'm sorry.
- Come with me. please.
Adama?
We found him this morning.
Your friend is apparently
convinced it was a shark.
I can guarantee you a shark did this.
If by some miracle
it did get through the locks.
why would it come to Paris?
I have no idea.
But when it was a beluga.
you didn't ask questions. did you?
Adama. call Angèle.
Mm-hmm.
- Follow me. please.
- Adama for Angèle. They're coming back.
Understood. Over.
It could've been a propeller.
It's happened before.
Trust me. Those are bite marks.
She's supposed to only measure 2.5 meters.
but she's far bigger.
And that same shark
is apparently in the Seine.
You can't possibly believe this.
It's ridiculous.
We've been following her.
We've gotta get her out
before she suffocates.
I don't understand. There are sharks
in the Thames too. and they don't...
The Thames is their natural habitat.
This shark. there's nothing for her here.
Her behavior isn't normal.
We have to get her out of the Seine.
And to do that. we need a team of experts.
It'll be a complicated operation.
Wait! Hang on a sec!
Why don't we make sure
that this shark exists? All right?
Will do.
Let's go.
Leo. Markus. We're leaving!
- Do you have a ping?
- Yeah. I do.
She's just behind l'Ile de la Cité.
200 meters from Notre-Dame.
We can take it from here.
No way. I'm coming with you.
That's out of the question.
Caro!
Here. This is what we'll do.
Lieutenant...
Not lieutenant. sergeant. Two seconds.
Sergeant or not.
what you're doing is completely useless.
By using my tracker.
we could very easily find her beacon.
And we could do that from up here!
Markus. Grab the harpoons.
There's no point in diving
and taking this risk.
Hey.
I just wanna know where it's hiding.
If it exists.
All right. guys. Let's go.
Are you coming?
This shark
is potentially dangerous!
And even more so
if she feels threatened by your team.
Ms. Assalas.
We're the River Brigade. not Greenpeace.
So either you show us
how your tracker works so we can use it.
or you come with us. but we're leaving.
Okay?
All right. let's go.
See you later.
Eight hundred meters!
Eight hundred meters.
She should be here.
River Police. this is Patrol Delta.
We're ready to head out.
Just give us the word. Over.
How deep is it here?
Five meters.
5.7 in the middle.
It's impossible. She's huge.
Where's she hiding?
Maybe we can't see her
because she doesn't exist.
Caro? Guys?
Synchronize trackers.
- I'm good.
- Yup.
- You see us?
- I've got you. yup.
River Police. this is
Patrol Delta. We read you loud and clear.
- Your lights?
- They're good.
All right. let's go.
Anything yet?
Pick up. pick up.
Where were you? I've been calling.
Disconnect her beacon now!
- They're gonna kill her.
- We'll lose her if I drop the beacon.
Do you not get it?
We don't have a choice! We have to.
We won't have a signal from her anymore.
it's too dangerous.
Just turn it off.
- We can't.
- Turn it off!
I don't know if I can reactivate it.
Ben. just do it. please!
Fine. I'll do it.
Hurry. we're running out of time.
She's coming.
Okay. the beacon's disconnected.
Great. Good. We did it.
Something's moving down there.
What's going on?
Oh shit. The signal...
- What do you mean "the signal"?
- I've lost it!
I don't understand what happened.
Where did it go?
Come on! Okay. okay. Move.
Hey! Sarge!
- Caro!
- Sarge! Sarge!
Hurry! Give me your hand!
Adil. I swear we felt
something down there.
It was enormous.
- You sure?
- Uh-huh.
We should check the sonar.
All units.
please respond. Armed robbery in progress.
Corner of Meslay and Du Temple.
Please respond.
Caro.
Get a broadcast ready.
Was it you?
- What?
- The beacon. Was that you?
The signal dropped.
I don't know what happened.
You endangered my whole team.
You think I would do that?
I told you not to dive!
- All right. get out.
- Huh?
Don't you touch me!
Stalled boat under Pont Marie.
I repeat. stalled boat
under the Pont Marie.
Come on.
We're heading back to base.
- That was a close call.
- I can't believe I listened to you.
- Wait. you're on their side now?
- I'm not. but what are we to do?
We've gotta get her back to the ocean!
She'll die if we don't.
- I may not be able to activate the beacon.
- Mika!
- What are you doing here?
- What were you thinking?
Sophia. they were armed!
Mika. what if she had attacked?
You know sharks would never attack
without good reason.
Lilith did that three years ago.
and I won't let it happen again.
But you weren't supposed to be there!
It was your fault!
You need to stay out of it. okay?
I didn't mean...
Sophia. I'm sorry!
Angèle.
if we're going to catch this shark.
we need to shut the locks immediately.
We need to stop boat traffic.
- We have no choice.
- You can't be serious.
One week till the triathlon.
Journalists from around the world
have been invited.
They're announcing that Olympic events
will take place in the Seine.
Yeah. I know.
Here you are asking me to call the mayor
and cancel everything?
How am I supposed to explain
something like that?
We're doubling our staff.
I'll call up the prefect.
We'll establish a surveillance team.
Restoring the health of our oceans
is imperative.
Our marine ecosystem
provides factually supported.
wide-reaching benefits
that can help us fight climate change.
Half of the oxygen...
SLAUGHTER AT SEA:
A GROUP OF SCIENTISTS ATTACKED BY A SHARK
Hello. we are currently
coming to you from the El Soldado.
a boat belonging
to the Ocean's Origins Association.
A few days ago. the crew was massacred
during an expedition north of Hawaii
near the Great Pacific Garbage Patch.
Oceans Origins' president.
Sophia Assalas. has refused to comment.
An investigation is underway.
What has more value than life?
I believe these images
speak for themselves.
I'm not trying to sell you anything.
I have no investors to convince
or elections to win.
but I and those after me
are about to lose everything.
Our parents... and their parents
have doomed us all.
My name is Mika.
I'm 20 years old.
We. at the Save Our Seas collective.
believe that an animal's life
is worth as much as a human's.
But a hundred million sharks
are murdered every year. Why?
To make them into soup
or an anti-aging cream?
We need to stop the slaughter.
We need to protect the sharks.
The ocean needs balance.
And decades of overfishing
have deprived sharks
of their food sources.
forcing them to hunt in new territories.
That's what happened to Lilith.
She got lost in the Seine.
and I need your help to save her.
We are the only ones left
who can make a difference.
And it starts with saving this shark.
Send a message.
Stand up to those who massacre our planet.
If we save her.
we scream at the top of our lungs
that this world belongs to us.
If we save her.
we save our future.
So join us.
Make yourselves heard.
Together. we'll find this shark.
and we're going to free her.
Ms. Assalas.
What are you doing here?
Uh... Look. I think the two of us
got off on the wrong foot.
I wanted to apologize.
Your nosebleed on the boat.
was that from the diving accident?
I didn't know about your husband.
Well. I mean... your team.
I just wanted to say I'm sorry.
Okay.
We've got a meeting with the mayor
of Paris this afternoon and I figured...
- Ms. Assalas...
- You can just call me Sophia.
Okay. Sophia. I was hoping
you'd come with us.
Because if I'm doing the talking.
it won't be good.
A shark?
There's a shark in the Seine?
If I insisted on meeting with you. ma'am.
it's because I believe this is urgent.
Of course. Angèle.
We have to take action.
You did the right thing.
Hmm.
You recognize it?
It's Paris.
My Paris.
Over there is everything we've built
for the upcoming triathlon.
Our showcase for the Olympics. as it were.
Journalists from around the world
will be here to cover the event.
We're expecting almost
a thousand participants?
Many more than that.
You see what I mean?
With all due respect.
civilians have already died.
Wait. hang on.
Believe it or not. I can sympathize.
- But Madam Mayor. if we do nothing. then...
- But no. No. Hey!
I don't like what you're insinuating here.
Then let me be very clear with you.
This species of shark is currently
experiencing huge behavioral shifts.
I first noticed these changes
three years ago. And I...
Yes. yes. We know all about your team.
There have been several deaths.
And if we do nothing.
it'll just get worse.
Your little PR stunt
will turn into a massacre.
- They didn't hear me.
- No.
Huh? You weren't listening?
1.7 billion!
That is how much
has already been spent by the State
to assure this event's success.
We even managed to install basins
under the Seine to recuperate wastewater.
That's 46.000 cubic meters.
I don't know what you want me to say.
Figure it out!
Make this little fish disappear!
Hm.
We understand. ma'am.
For our part. our teams will handle
containing the news on social media.
I need you to know
failure is not an option.
This event will be perfect. Yes? And fun.
All right. Angèle. go!
I'll walk you back. This way.
Sophia. get me a list
of the equipment you'll need for this.
I've already started
getting everything together.
But since we can't track Lilith anymore.
we need a way to lure her.
How do we do that?
We can bait her. Between the Pont de Sully
and the Pont d'Austerlitz.
Once tranquilized. we'll take her
to the locks at the Port de l'Arsenal.
And the Oceanography Institute
will handle the rest.
Understood?
Right. let's move.
Make sure your lights are charged up.
we'll need 'em down there.
I can hold her for 30 minutes.
I understand. but we can't afford to wait.
- Shit!
- Hey. be careful with that.
Come on. man.
- Sorry.
- Lift. One. two.
Do your best
and get over here ASAP.
Got it. I'm good.
Is the lid not sealed?
Congrats.
I got the Institute on the phone.
They're ready.
Wait. I need to show you a video.
Back to work. boss.
Look at this.
Once she's been tranquilized.
we have to move quickly.
The Institute will only have
30 minutes to move her.
After that. she'll suffocate.
We'll use the same equipment
as those guys?
- Mm-hm.
- Sophia! I have to talk to you. now.
Ben. where are they?
In the catacombs.
By the wastewater reservoirs.
Please don't tell her I came to see you.
I care about her.
but she's out of control.
She's hoping to prove we can guide
Lilith back to the ocean using sonar...
How'd you find the shark?
I figured out a way to reactivate
her beacon. Easier than I thought.
How did you pull that off?
Could you show us. please?
What's she doing down there?
- Those are the old catacombs.
- Exactly.
They're the city's water reservoirs.
It's like an underground lake.
You can't access the reservoirs
from the Seine. It's impossible.
You actually can.
We found a condemned entrance
under the Canal St-Martin.
- When were you planning to go?
- They're already there.
And there's gonna be a lot of people.
Damn it.
I shouldn't have come to you.
No. Ben. wait. it's okay.
Listen. No one can dive.
Make sure Mika doesn't.
Just head back there.
pretend nothing happened. We're coming.
Okay?
Thanks for coming.
I'm glad you're all here.
Thanks for your support.
Thank you all.
Regis? Get logged on. You good?
Is it ready?
Almost.
- You sure about this?
- Yeah.
I'm sure this will work.
- It'll bring her straight to us.
- That's not what I'm worried about.
Don't tell me
you're doubting the plan now.
Aren't we doing what we promised?
What if this doesn't work?
What if we do nothing?
Okay.
This is River One for Chronos.
I'm in the catacombs.
near St-Martin. Jemapes side.
We may have as many
as 50 people down here.
Requesting backup.
I repeat. urgent request for backup.
All right. guys.
We don't know when backup is coming.
so our safety is paramount. okay?
Check your lights.
Do not get between them and the water.
Stay close to the walls.
There's only one way out. so we've gotta
keep everybody calm and avoid a panic.
Otherwise they'll bottleneck.
get trampled.
We good? Adama. Leo. on the right.
Sophia. stay with them.
Nils and Markus with me.
Everybody. keep calm!
Police. Out of the water. now!
No. no. wait.
- Let's go!
- Hang on!
Come on! Party's over! This area
is strictly off-limits to the public.
We're going to evacuate calmly.
My colleagues will bring you to the exit.
Adama!
You'll follow Adama and Markus.
- Let's go!
- No. wait!
- Come on!
- No. wait! We're almost there!
We ask you to step back. please.
The ground is very slippery here.
Just wait!
We know what we're doing!
Mika!
Sophia. we can help her
back to the ocean. trust me.
Against the wall!
You need to let go of that
and get out of there.
Right. come on! Let's go! Pick it up! Go!
We're moving! Let's go. let's go!
Everybody out! Let's go!
- I'm talking to you! Go!
- She's coming!
Look. There's another one.
There's two! Holy shit!
- Is it a baby?
- She had a baby.
Mika. don't touch her.
Lilith is gonna feel threatened.
Did you hear me? Get out of the water!
Lilith is dangerous.
- Sophia. look at this.
- Nils...
I was right. Trust me!
- Cover me.
- You're not listening. Mika!
Lilith had a baby!
We've invaded her nest!
Wake the hell up. They won't hurt anyone.
Mika. get out of there!
She's gonna attack! Get out of the water!
Mika! Get out of there right now!
That's an order! Backs against the wall!
- Away from the edge!
- Calm down.
- We're gonna evacuate.
- Against the wall.
- Against the wall!
- Mika. get out of there!
Stay against the wall!
Do something. Adil. now!
- Stay back!
- Over here! Adil!
Adil!
Adil. what the hell?
Get outta there! Hurry!
- Mika!
- Mika. get out! Mika!
Get out of there!
Mika! No!
Adil!
Hurry up. Adil!
Stay away from the edge! Against the wall!
Everyone. follow me! This way! Move!
- This way!
- We're all gonna die!
Give me your hand. now! I'm here!
- Give me your hand!
Ah!
Over here. Ben! Ben!
Gimme your hand!
Ben!
Get me out of here! Help!
Ben! Ben! Ben!
Let's move it! Come on!
Let's move! Don't stop. run!
- Keep going!
- Watch out! Move over! Give me your hand!
Ah!
- Leopold!
- Leo!
Get out of the water! Over here!
Everyone. out! Swim to the side!
They're everywhere!
Hurry! Come on!
It's right behind us!
Hey! Give me your hand! Over here!
- This way! Hurry!
- I've got you!
Just get to the exits!
Leo! Leo! No!
Leo!
Come on! Move it!
- Hey! This way!
- Move it!
Come on!
Leo!
- Leo!
Over here!
Hurry. come on!
Give me your hand!
Hey. look at me! Look at me!
You okay? She's stable now?
It's the prefect!
- Oh!
- Angèle...
- Adil. Here. come on!
- Two seconds. two seconds!
I'm feeling okay. actually.
Yeah. I...
It was my fault. Adil.
I was supposed to protect them.
Sophia.
It's not your fault.
Okay?
Adil?
We need you.
Now.
- What's going on?
- Take a look.
You see that?
These organs allow the shark
to adapt to the salinity of the water.
And you see this protrusion
on the side here?
That shows she adapted to fresh water.
But why are they in Paris?
As they were swimming up the Seine.
they must've found
the perfect place to breed.
They figured they'd be safe
in the catacombs.
A little bit like...
larvae in a hive. you know?
They'll feed in the Seine.
mature. and then return to the ocean.
Paris is one of the rare cities
that can support this kind of ecosystem.
She's a female.
That's not possible.
She hasn't reached sexual maturity.
but she's already pregnant?
I don't understand.
You see that? The size of her teeth?
That proves she's only two months old.
It's incredible.
Is there an explanation?
Lilith is reproducing by parthenogenesis.
What does that mean?
She doesn't need a male to get pregnant.
Adil. I made a mistake.
These aren't makos.
They've adapted.
Lilith is the first
of a brand-new species.
And if we do nothing.
they'll continue to reproduce.
And they won't stop. Ever.
Twelve dead.
This puts a real damper
on my celebrations.
Ma'am. by the time
we arrived on site. it was too late.
We tried to get everyone out.
We did our best. unfortunately...
Your superiors should have been notified.
Carrying out this operation on your own
was beyond your capabilities.
With all due respect.
we did our best to inform the mayor.
You did not. That's completely untrue.
You "informed me"
about a lost shark in the Seine.
I trusted that your team and you
were capable of handling the situation.
I'm under so much stress.
The triathlon starts tomorrow.
Can you imagine
how much shit I'll have to face?
I'll go on the news.
but I don't know what to say.
You don't know what to say?
Are you serious?
You understand people died?
Tell them there's a shark
in the Seine. it's the truth.
Right. Listen. why don't we calm down...
Do you not understand what's happening?
A dozen dead. and it could be hundreds!
You just have to cancel.
it's not complicated!
Hey!
Get out of my office right now.
And you.
get back to managing barge traffic.
As of this moment.
the army's in charge of security. got it?
Mr. Prefect. hush this up immediately.
Nothing can get out.
Massive purification basins
have been installed
uh. just beside the nautical sites.
As you know. the swimming
competition will be held there.
And this means every Parisian
will be able to go for a swim themselves
after a long day at work.
And what is your response
to those who claim
there are sharks on the loose
in the Seine?
Oh. well. if this were true. okay.
I would be thrilled.
That would indicate that our efforts
to depollute were met with success.
- You're thrilled to have sharks?
- Absolutely!
In any case. it's common knowledge that
sharks are perfectly harmless to humans.
As far as I'm concerned.
sharks of all kinds...
- We really messed up.
- Enough of this shark talk.
Now they're making us the scapegoats.
That's politicians for you.
They never want to admit
when they're wrong.
It's frustrating to be ignored.
To not be able to help.
The army's taking care of it.
If Lilith and her pack use the Seine
to head back to the ocean tomorrow.
it'll be carnage.
- We have to do something. Adil.
- Stop it.
This whole thing is out of our hands.
So just stop.
Why did you leave the army?
- Adil...
- Because I was scared.
We were supposed to free some journalists
taken hostage in Burkina Faso.
And I was afraid of dying.
So I abandoned my brothers-in-arms.
They managed to free the hostages. but...
they took some serious casualties.
That's why I left the army.
- Something to drink?
- No. I'm good.
So...
What should we do?
Got a plan?
I need two or three people
to make this work.
No one's under any obligation.
We only have a few hours
till the triathlon.
so anyone who doesn't want to. you...
For Leo.
We're a team. aren't we?
I'm really sorry. I've got a family.
But you know what?
I can still cover you all.
The nest must be here. in this crypt.
Just underneath the catacomb chamber.
This is Poiccard and Berruti.
These men specialize in explosives.
Berruti will lead the first team.
which consists of
Sophia. Adama and myself.
Caro and Markus.
you'll wait on the surface.
You'll be positioned
at the exit of the tunnel.
Our extraction point is here.
behind Notre-Dame.
While you're heading there.
we'll dive from the catacomb chamber.
The trench is 30 meters deep.
We'll have to make a decompression stop.
At the bottom. there's a tunnel
approximately 20 meters long.
Once we're in the crypt.
we'll place explosives
so everything collapses at once.
How long will we have before they blow?
- Less than three minutes.
- It's suicide.
There won't be time to decompress
before we surface.
We'll use Seabobs
to get through the tunnel.
Once we're inside. we're in the clear.
Then we travel 80 meters
to get back to the Seine.
Markus. you cut the drainage tunnel grate.
then you rejoin Caro at the surface.
And as for me.
I'll be accompanying the mayor.
I'll cover as best I can from there.
And what if the sharks are out for a swim?
I'll be using an infrasound emitter.
It will attract the sharks and keep them
in the crypt while you lay the explosives.
We'll also have powerful lights
to hold them off.
and we'll be fully equipped
to dive and communicate easily.
It's the same gear
that I used with my team.
- Who triggers the detonator?
- I do.
I'll make sure we're at a safe distance.
then boom.
Any questions?
What if you don't come back up?
We're almost there.
Thirty meters down.
All right. let's go.
Coast is clear.
This way. everyone.
Over here. please.
Get the other side. Go.
All right. everybody. come this way!
Let's go!
This is 75. bridge secured.
We're secure down here too.
We've got Bravo group
setting up. Should be just another five.
Turn around!
No one gets through! Turn around!
Hey! Take it easy.
we're the River Brigade.
We're the police.
The military's in charge now!
You should've received your orders.
Turn around. Let's go!
Caro for Angèle. They won't let us pass.
Caro for Angèle.
Good luck. everyone.
Excuse me. mayor. Just a moment?
How are you feeling about today?
Fantastic.
We've been working
on this event for months.
and it wouldn't have been possible
without my team.
and the support of the prefect.
In terms of the security of today's event.
there have been rumors
of sharks in the Seine.
Those are just rumors. and we hope...
I want to assure you
every precaution has been taken
to guarantee this event's security.
- Thanks.
- I have another question for the mayor...
There you have it.
Stay with us for live updates as the mayor
prepares to address the crowd
and launch the triathlon.
With the mayor having arrived
with her team of advisors.
we should be getting underway
very shortly.
...banks of the Seine
alongside triathletes
ready to take the plunge.
The mayor of Paris...
Caro for Angèle. What do we do?
My team needs to pass
to handle an emergency.
The prefect has ordered a police presence
behind Notre-Dame.
Over.
Copy that.
Caro for Adil. We were delayed.
We'll be there in ten. Over.
Copy that.
There's still another 20 meters.
Adama. pass me the emitter.
Here we are! My fellow Parisians!
For some. it was a dream.
For others. just a talking point.
I have done it!
This is our Paris!
Safe! Vibrant! A Paris for everyone!
Adil for Caro.
We're in the crypt.
Are you in position?
Adil for Caro.
We're almost there.
Two more minutes.
Over.
All right.
Shit...
No sudden movements. Just stay calm.
Let us never forget.
Paris is. and will forevermore be.
a place for celebration!
All right!
Ooh!
I'd like to declare
the triathlon of the Seine.
open!
Ooh!
Hello again! Welcome back to all those
who've been following the opening.
Welcome to the Paris triathlon...
The race has officially kicked off.
All right!
Yes!
They're off! The first round
of the Seine triathlon has begun.
Angèle for Caro.
The swimmers are in.
The first round is underway. Hurry.
Markus just dove. Over.
You can go.
Can you see her?
Negative.
Caro. what's your status?
Working on it. It won't be long now.
I don't understand.
She's still not here.
The swimmers are in fine form
for this third round
of the Seine triathlon.
But there are still seven rounds to go.
Something's wrong.
Where is she?
The coast is clear.
Copy that.
Come on. We have to hurry.
Are the explosives ready?
Mine are.
Ready to go here.
- Poiccard?
- Two minutes.
- Let's go. They look nervous.
- Just a second!
Wait. she's still not here.
Okay. Explosive placed.
Almost there.
Okay. it's all good here.
Everyone head for the exit
and I'll initiate the blast.
Help!
Hurry!
- Berruti! Berruti. come on!
- Help!
Nobody move.
We have to stick together.
No! Adama!
- Come back. Adama!
- Get outta here!
Hurry! Let's go! I'm setting it off!
Move!
No!
- Over there! Sophia!
- Sophia!
- Sophia! Adil!
- Swim!
Swim! Come on! Over here!
- Faster! Come on!
- Swim!
Give me your arm!
Come on!
You're okay.
Sophia! The others?
Adil. wake up.
Adil. Can you hear me?
It's okay.
Sophia! What are you doing?
Sophia!
- She's right here!
- Sophia!
- We gotta get out of here!
- Hurry up!
- Swim! Hurry! Come on!
- Come on!
- Swim. Sophia!
- Hurry!
Adil!
Why's she circling?
She's not. She's headed for the swimmers.
Come on!
...for this third round
of the Seine triathlon.
There are still seven rounds to go.
Oh! Oh! Oh!
All right!
There's a shark!
- Under the water. look out!
- Shark!
Shark! There's a shark!
What're you doing? What's going on?
A fin. Did you see that?
There's a shark. Film it. come on!
Give me your hand!
Behind you. look out!
Stop! Cease fire immediately!
There are shells!
Hey! Cease fire!
- Stop!
- There are shells!
There are live shells! Hey!
This way. come on!
Run. everybody! Run!
Out of my way!
Out of my way. you idiots!
Oh shit! Run! Run!
Come on!
Adil?
Adil!
Adil.
Sophia.
Is it over?
UNDER PARIS
IN MEMORY OF JIMMY CAVÉ
AND BRUNO VERSTRAETE